Subject Files
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  - Subject files: High Adventure with Lowell Thomas (From the Persian Gulf to Zanzibar), 1959 March; 7 (Box 1548)
    - Note: [Letter from Lowell Thomas to Ed Heffron, 14 May 1980] Dear Ed Heffron, Three of these pictures were taken on an expedition in Australia. The old boy with the white beard and the heavy eyebrows is an Australian Drover. He was a well known character in the Australian Outback. Which I had a copy of that one. I've forgotten what they call the little animals on my arm. They actually look like dragons, and evidently are rather rare. We encountered them deep in the interior of Australia when we were on an expedition. The man chatting with me in the picture where I'm sitting on the front of a Land Rover, is an Australian film producer named Lee Robinson who was directing the making of our film. Behind us is what the Australians consider one of the wonders of the world, Ayers Rock. They say it is the largest single rock in the world and is several miles in circumference. The one with the young lady was made in a palace in the Atlas Mountains, in Morocco. And the one where I'm sitting at a table with a mask beside me was made in what was known as the Belgian Congo on the shores of Lake Albert. Sincerely, Lowell Thomas; P.S. All the pictures were probably all taken in 1958, 2
    - [Australia, signed Lowell Thomas], 3
    - [Australia, signed Lowell Thomas], 4
    - [Unknown, signed Lowell Thomas], 5
    - [signed Lowell Thomas, The Congo 1958], 6
  - Subject files: High Adventure with Lowell Thomas (miscellaneous), 1957 - 1959; 8 (Box 1548)
    - LT on junk in Hong Kong harbor, 1
    - Verso: LT on junk in Hong Kong harbor, 1-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas sitting with people from his High Adventures], 2
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with a man; taken during his High Adventures], 3
  - Subject files: High Adventure with Lowell Thomas (Dorothy Barton), 1961 September; 9 (Box 1548)
    - [Lowell Thomas talking with Dorothy Barton during his High Adventure], 1
    - [Lowell Thomas and Dorothy Barton; taken during his High Adventure], 2
    - Note: [letter from Dorothy [Barton] to Lowell Thomas], 3
  - Subject files: May Hoag, undated; 10 (Box 1548)
    - Note: Old spinster lady, Quaker Hill, gave talk to school children on her 100th birthday, 1
    - Old spinster lady, Quaker Hill, gave talk to school children on her 100th birthday, 2
    - Old spinster lady, Quaker Hill, gave talk to school children on her 100th birthday, 3
  - Subject files: President Herbert Hoover, undated; 11 (Box 1548)
    - [Herbert Hoover, right, Harry G. Thomas, second from right], 1
    - Verso: Herbert Hoover, Harry G. Thomas, 1-verso
    - [Herbert Hoover, second from right, Harry G. Thomas, third from right], 2
    - Verso: Herbert Hoover, Harry G. Thomas, 2-verso
    - [Herbert Hoover, seated second from right, Lowell Thomas, standing second from left, Prosper Buranelli, standing fourth from right], 3
  - Subject files: Bob and Dolores Hope, undated; 12 (Box 1548)
    - [Lowell Thomas with Dolores and Bob Hope], 1
    - [New Years Card from Bob and Dolores Hope & family], 2
  - Subject files: Horses and other animals, undated; 13 (Box 1548)
    - [Horse and its baby], 1
    - [Two cows], 2
    - [A herd of sheep], 3
    - [Horses, sheep, and cows], 4
  - Subject files: King Hussein of Jordan, 1964; 14 (Box 1548)
    - Toastmaster Lowell Thomas, who needs no introduction to any audience, presents His Majesty, King Hussein of Jordan to an audience of nearly a thousand people at a dinner given by Near East Foundation in honor of the Jordanian Monarch. The Foundation has been engaged with the Jordanian government in a cooperative program of technical assistance and community development, 1
    - Note: Toastmaster Lowell Thomas, who needs no introduction to any audience, presents His Majesty, King Hussein of Jordan to an audience of nearly a thousand people at a dinner given by Near East Foundation in honor of the Jordanian Monarch. The Foundation has been engaged with the Jordanian government in a cooperative program of technical assistance and community development, 2
    - Caption: To my very good friend Lowell Thomas, wish very great wishes [?] signed King Hussein 29.6.64, 3
    - Toastmaster Lowell Thomas and Dinner Chairman Mrs. Robert Howe Baldwin engage His Majesty, King Hussein, in conversation as the receiving line is forming, 4
    - Note: Toastmaster Lowell Thomas and Dinner Chairman Mrs. Robert Howe Baldwin engage His Majesty, King Hussein, in conversation as the receiving line is forming, 5
    - Mr. Lowell Thomas greets King Hussein's brother, His Royal Highness Prince Hasan Ibn Talal, as Mrs. Baldwin, His Majesty and Mr. Cleveland Dodge look on, 6
    - Note: Mr. Lowell Thomas greets King Hussein's brother, His Royal Highness Prince Hasan Ibn Talal, as Mrs. Baldwin, His Majesty and Mr. Cleveland Dodge look on, 7
  - Subject files: International Platform Association (IPA), 1974; 15 (Box 1548)
    - Leon Jaworski; I.P.A. Governor and President and Lowell Thomas; I.P.A. Convention, July 31, 1974; Photo by Irving Green, 2709 Heath Ave., Bronx, N.Y. 10463, 1
    - Verso: Leon Jaworski; I.P.A. Governor and President and Lowell Thomas; I.P.A. Convention, July 31, 1974; Photo by Irving Green, 2709 Heath Ave., Bronx, N.Y. 10463, 1-verso
  - Subject files: International Radio & Television Society (IRTS), circa 1970s; 16 (Box 1548)
    - Behind Tomm. [Lowell Thomas] and Bill Leonard is Wally Schwartz head of Blair Telev. on left John Creamer, Chair of Bd of Creamer Inc., 1
    - Verso: Behind Tomm. [Lowell Thomas] and Bill Leonard is Wally Schwartz head of Blair Telev. on left John Creamer, Chair of Bd of Creamer Inc., 1-verso
    - Bill Leonard head of CBS News, 2
    - Verso: Bill Leonard head of CBS News, 2-verso
    - Bill Small head of N.B.C. News, 3
    - Verso: Bill Small head of N.B.C. News, 3-verso
    - Also Don Creamer and Jack Fritz - head of Blair, 4
    - Verso: Also Don Creamer and Jack Fritz - head of Blair, 4-verso
    - Howard Meaghans, 5
    - Verso: Howard Meaghans, 5-verso
    - Jane Pauley, 6
    - Verso: Jane Pauley, 6-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas talking to other members of the International Radio and Television Society], 7
    - [Lowell Thomas shaking hands with a member of the International Radio and Television Society], 8
    - [Lowell Thomas speaking with a member of the International Radio and Television Society], 9
    - [Lowell Thomas and a member of the International Radion and Television Society], 10
    - [Lowell Thomas talking with other memebers of the International Radio and Television Society], 11
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas and other members of the International Radio and Television Society], 12
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas and other members of the International Radio and Television Society], 13
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas giving a speech at the International Radio and Television Society event], 14
  - Subject files: Iran avalanche, 1942; 17 (Box 1548)
    - What it looked like close-up, after 10 days of digging. Col. Hayne and Fayal and Persian workmen; Avalanche of snow in Elburg Mount [?], Iran - May-1942-from Major Gordon [?] U.S Military Attache, Kabul, Afghanistan, 1
    - Verso: What it looked like close-up, after 10 days of digging. Col. Hayne and Fayal and Persian workmen; Avalanche of snow in Elburg Mount [?], Iran - May-1942-from Major Gordon [?] U.S Military Attache, Kabul, Afghanistan, 1-verso
  - Subject files: Shah of Iran, circa 1960s; 18 (Box 1548)
    - L.T. with the Shah of Persia, 1
    - Verso: L.T. with the Shah of Persia, 1-verso
    - L.T. with the Shah of Persia, 2
    - L.T. with the Shah of Persia, 3
  - Subject files: Ireland, 1974; 19 (Box 1548)
    - [Ireland], 1
    - Note: Heimacy?[?] Ireland 194 [1974?], 2
  - Subject files: Japan, Kayoko Nezu, 1961; 20 (Box 1548)
    - My city is a snow festival. Snow a work of art, The first rank. Silk Road, 19 February 1961, 1
    - Verso: My city is a snow festival. Snow a work of art, The first rank. Silk Road, 19 February 1961, 1-verso
    - Note: [letter from Kayoko Nezu to Lowell Thomas], [PDF], 2
  - Subject files: Japan, The Old Castle of Himeji [three dimensional color photograph], undated; 21 (Box 1548)
    - [Japan, The Old Castle of Himeji], 1
  - Subject files: Howard Jarvis, circa 1970s; 22 (Box 1548)
    - Howard Jarvis - Tax man from California; was it "Proposition 13" ?, 1
    - Verso: Howard Jarvis - Tax man from California; was it "Proposition 13" ?, 1-verso
  - Subject files: President Lyndon Baines Johnson, 1968; 23 (Box 1548)
    - Interrupted by L.B.J. when I was addressing the National Association of Broadcasters, 1
    - Note: Interrupted by L.B.J. when I was addressing the National Association of Broadcasters, 2
  - Subject files: Irving Johnson (The Yankee), undated; 24 (Box 1548)
    - Robert Johnson meets a 200-year old Galapagos turtle, 1
    - Verso: Robert Johnson meets a 200-year old Galapagos turtle, 1-verso
    - Commander Irving Johnson, 2
    - Verso: Commander Irving Johnson, 2-verso
    - The mysterious statues of Easter Island, 3
    - Verso: The mysterious statues of Easter Island, 3-verso
    - Adrien LeMayuer a Belgian artist, and Electra Johnson in front of one of his paintings of his beautiful Balinese wife., 4
    - Verso: Adrien LeMayuer a Belgian artist, and Electra Johnson in front of one of his paintings of his beautiful Balinese wife., 4-verso
    - The Yankee-Commander Irving Johnson, 5
    - Verso: The Yankee-Commander Irving Johnson, 5-verso
  Box 1549 - Box 1552
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  Box 1553 - Box 1556
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  Box 1557 - Box 1560
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  Box 1561 - Box 1565
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6